Zhiqiang Xu | Senior software architect

☐ +86 135 8561 8661 • ☐ +1 805 669 8661 • C +86 21 6766 3700

☑ xeonxu@gmail.com • ☐ blog.xeonxu.info • ☐ xeonxu • ☑ xeonxu

☐ Birth:1983.11 Age:35

SUMMARY

BA. With 13 years embeded software develop expriences. Including 2yrs on vehicle related projects, 5yrs on mobile phone projects, and 3yrs on robot related projects.

Excellent in C, bash, linux, rt-thread, version control, docker.

Be familiar with software design, problem solving and debuging skills.

Experience on refactoring robot control system using ROS and docker technic. Using RTOS to implement STM32 based sensors.

2yrs experience on team management.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Shanghai Yunshen technologies Co., Ltd.

Shanghai 2018.06 – Present

Senior System architect

Work content: robot development

Main work:

- Sensor development
 - implement rt-thread's CAN driver for STM32.
 - Develop ultrasonic, anti-colllision, anti-falling sensors. Report sensors' infomations by CAN bus.
 - Implement CAN bus based OTA function for sensors.
- o Robot control system
 - Use docker image to package ROS enviroment.
 - Integrate camera driver and CAN adaptor driver in docker image.
 - Write ROS node to connect between drivers and applications.
 - Export clone system method for producing in factories.
 - Router configuration for robot.
 - Use repo method to manage robot softwares.
 - Implement OTA function for X86 based controller.
- System management
 - Docker registry server.
 - LDAP, Git, gerrit, vpn and jenkins server management.
 - ROS(Router Operating System)'s QoS configuration.

Shanghai clever mrobot technologies Co., Ltd.

Shanghai 2016.07 – 2018.05

Senior Embeded Software Engineer Work content: robot development

Main work:

- o Android driver development
 - Based on Rockwell 3288 platform. Solving charging issues.
 - Stability optimization.
- o Robot control system
 - Redesign robot control system using ROS.
 - Use ROS(Robot Operating System) to construct control system for robotic products.
 - Integrate OpenCV support on TX1.

Shanghai Phicomm. Inc.

Shanghai

Embeded Software Engineer

2010.06 - 2016.06

Work content: Mobile phone development

Main work:

- Android Smartphone project
 - Develop on Marvell PXA968 platform. Sensors' and PMIC's drivers. Logo file generator.
 - Qualcomm MSM7x27/MSM8x25/MSM8x25Q platform. PMIC module, develop environment optimize. Mainly, PMIC module development, geomagnetic debug method optimization, TP fw upgrade method and dual-way charging method based on smb358. Batch review tool for gerrit.
 - Qualcomm MSM8x10/8x12/8x26/8x16/8994/8909 platform. PMIC module, battery charactorization.
- o MStar and MTK feature phone project
 - MMI custimization, add SP for customer.
 - Write auto release script.

Shanghai iBingo network technology Co., Ltd.

Shanghai

Embeded software engineer

2009.10 - 2010.06

Work content: Develop dynamic theme and screen saver for feature phone (iShow theme system). Main work:

- o Develop dynamic themes for feature phone base on MTK platform.
 - 3X3 style, Ring style theme.
 - Ribbon style screensaver.
 - Dandelion screensaver which can distinction between day and light.
 - Auto release script.
- o Optimize downloading efficiency.

Shanghai Dragontec Group

Shanghai

Embeded Software Engineer

2008.11 - 2009.10

Work content: Japanese outsourcing software project.

Main work:

- o Digital TV develop project from Hitachi.
 - UI implement and bug fixment.
 - Write documentation.
 - Code and test.
- o System port from vxworks to Linux. Develop environment improvement.
- o Openvg port project.
 - Port opency support to SuperH platform for Hitachi television project.
 - Write unit test cases.

Kyrocera Mita Oosaka

Java Engineer 2008.06 – 2008.11

Work content: Use Java to develop a non-paper work solution for hospital, which is called KMCapture Solution.

Main work:

- o Work for implementing Controller, Facade and Storage modules.
- o Write documentation.
- o Code and test.

Hitachi ICS Hitachi

Embeded Software Engineer

2007.05 - 2008.06

Work content: Work for developing a car audio equipment for Cadillac CTS 08 and 09.

Main work:

- o iPod interface and control system.
- o Parser for getting informations from audio file.
- Write documentation.

Nanking University Dragontec

Nanking

Java Software Engineer

2006.07 - 2007.05

Work content: Develop online management system for suntory's vending machines.

Main work:

- Write database process using sql.
- o Auto release and deployment script.
- o Write unit test cases.
- Write documentation.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Hohai University Nanking

BA of Traffic engineering 2002.09 - 2006.06

LANGUAGE SKILLS

English: CET4

Japanese:

Normal

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGES

C: Proficient Java: Poor

Linux/Unix:ProficientHardware:Ease solderingScript:BashEditor:Emacs/Vim

HOBBIES

Reading: Technology, Novell Sports: Skate Board, F1, Marathon

GRANTED PANTENTS

201510477097.X: 一种登录认证方法及系统

201510612722.7: 一种扩展移动终端运算能力的系统 **201410613796.8**: 一种移动终端及其虚拟光驱的实现方法

201210368281.7: 一种耳机接口装置及基于所述耳机接口装置的控制方法

201510745100.1: 一种密钥加密方法及系统、电子设备

201210585845.2: 硬件固件独立升级系统及方法

201420615063.3: 一种手机进水保护装置

MISCELLANOUS

o twip: Add proxy support.

- o ChinaDNS-C: Bug fix and add compile target for tomato.
- \circ Koreader: Bug fix and compilation speed optimize.
- o battery_analyzer: Use spline to generate battery SOC table.
- o vim_configs: Vim configure used for co-workers.